Curriculum Vitae: February 9, 2014

Han Boetes Römerstraße 6 4083 Lebring Österreich Born on August 1, 1969 **2**+43 6 8181 5268 21 mailto:hboetes@gmail.com http://homepage.boetes.org/

Drivers license: passenger car



Objective:

A working environment is by definition unfinished, with room for much improvement. My main ambition is to improve the working environment into one that is sturdier, safer, more organized, and well-documented. I also like to share my vision with colleagues, and inspire them to improve our environment. This is crucial towards ensuring new features can be rolled out successfully.

IT Knowledge and experience:

Installation, maintainance, kernel configuration, isc-bind, isc-dhcpd, unbound, Samba, nfs, Apache, nginx, vsftpd, CVS, git, openntpd, postfix, exim, dovecot, procmail, spamassassin, MailScanner, squid, OpenSSH, vmware, kvm, virtualbox, lxc, keepalived, mysql, Solaris, Debian, Redhat, Centos, OpenBSD.

Security:

Unix permissions: the very basics of unix security, yet I rarely find a server

which doesn't contain mistakes. **Firewalls:** iptables, pf, altq. **Networking:** cisco switches.

Crypto: OpenSSH, IPSEC, OpenVPN, gnupg.

IDS: Snort, packetfence.

Monitoring: Nagios, cacti, monit, logfile analysis.

Integration/SSO: LDAP, kerberos, freeipa.

Hardening: closing down unneeded services, setting up access lists, log-analysis,

applying patches, install intrusion detection.

Code: Principles of secure coding, Code auditing.

Coding assistance:

I actively help with Open Source development. I'm experienced in: **Debugging:** Installation of beta-software using snapshots or CVS, debugging with GDB, systematic searching, reporting bugs, testing and submitting patches.

Communication: Discuss bugs and feature requests with coders and endusers using e-mail or IRC.

Documentation: I write compact, clear and well typesetted documentation in various formats such as HTML, LATEX and mandoc. I prefer writing documentation in wiki format.

Coding:

Shell-scripts: I write shell- or bash-scripts for systemengineers and end-users to simplify tasks. I write in clear style with lot's of comments. For example: install_latest_kernel ¹

C: I'm also experienced in C basics, which is very practical for various tasks like debugging, compiling, porting and creating small functions and applications like: fbsetbg²

Hardware and Datacenters:

Task oriented acquirement and construction of computers and peripherals. Finding and replacing defective parts. Reusage of old hardware. Lots of experience in datacenters with mounting, patching and labeling. I'm ESD certified.

Cisco

I have experience with Cisco switches and I certainly want to get certified and learn more about them

Education and coaching:

I'm experienced in educating and coaching unix engineers through years of experience on IRC and at Utelisys were we were constantly searching for youngsters gifted in ICT. Also I have educated fellow engineers on various levels with their jobs.

¹http://homepage.boetes.org/software/install_latest_kernel/

²http://homepage.boetes.org/software/fbsetbg/fbsetbg.html

System Maintainance: Tactical and Strategical:

System maintainance is a very special kind of job. You have to be able to keep a working system running and at the same time improve it in a very controlled fashion. This requires insight, creativity, modisty, wisdom, stress resistance, creativity, flexibility, diplomacy, focus and endurance.

This makes system maintaince an always fascinating and challenging profession for me.

Relevant Work Experience:

Maart 2013 — ; work at Axis Flight training systems GmbH

Work environment: Oracle linux, ubuntu, debian, windows, MacOSX, cisco, zimbra, redmine, mediawiki, vmware, bind, apache.

2012 — Feb 2013; work at JM-DATA GmbH

Work environment: Solaris, Redhat Linux, Directadmin, kickstart, freeipa, cnadmin, 2nd line support

2009 — 2012; work at Utelisys B.V.

Work environment: Gentoo Linux, Debian Linux, CentOS, FreeBSD, pfSense, SNMP, LDAP, monit, nagios, Cacti, Squid, mediawiki, postfix, spamassassin, Cisco.

Job at a small IPS where I managed customers contacts, managed the mailservers, nameserver, backupservers, webservers and monitoring and learned the basics of Cisco and helped with setting up the Hotel Casa400 internet/telephony/TV infrastructure. All in all a very versatile and interesting workspot. I was the senior Unix Administrator.

2007 — 2009; work at Snow B.V.

Period 2008-11 — 2009-7

Various internal projects including:

PHP application which could brand PDF-files with the company logo. PHP facebook application which allows people to drag names on pictures. Set up a Solaris jumpstart server with a very complete setup which can also install a solaris 8 zone.

Period 2008-7 — 2008-11

Organisation: Telecom company.

Work environment: Debian Linux, FreeBSD, Cacti, pfSense, SNMP, Squid, mediawiki, windows.

Produce documentation for organisation.

Installation of UPS integration including software and documentation.

Assist remote installation at foreign locations.

Daily maintainance of remote Unix servers.

Improving squid proxy performance.

Period 2008-4 — 2008-7

Organisation: Internet Service Provider. Work environment: Sun Solaris Unix, Debian.

Configuration management.

Maintainaning configuration database.

Migrating documentationsystem to a new platform.

Implementation and documentation of remote console access hardware.

Daily maintainance of unix servers.

Datacenter maintainance.

Period 2008-1 — 2008-4

Organisation: Internet Service Provider.

Working environment: Datacenter maintainance, ITIL, ESD.

Hardware: Sun.

Migration and set-up of many sun servers for the fusion of various internet providers.

Patching, labeling, upgrading firmware, configuring ILOM.

Period 2007-9 — 2008-1

Organisation: Internet Service Provider.

Task: Installation of SinglEview billing application.

Action: Write well commented script that reproduces the complete installation.

Period 2007-7 — 2007-9

Practical Prince2 training by writing PIDs and Mandates for internal projects for Snow ltd.

2000 — 2007: Working independently.

Support and system maintainance for companies and private people.

System maintainance at Stiching Kelderwerk³ for their website, forum, network and hardware.

Creating the Atlantis Meestertienkamp⁴ website.

Installation, configuration and maintainance of Linux and OpenBSD server

³http://kelderwerk.nl/

⁴http://cafeatlantis.nl/meestertienkamp2007/

and firewalls for private users, small companies and institutions.

Volunteer maintainance of packages for OpenBSD, Mandrake- and Crux-linux; support via IRC, e-mail. Bug hunting and solving.

Migrating MS-windows to Linux. End user support for MS-windows.

1998 – 2000: Telecom maintainance via InterCAI and Randstad

Telecom maintainance for Delft municipal: Daily maintainance. Database mutations. PBX mutations. User support. Contact with Suppliers.

Telecom maintainance at Schiphol: User support. Voice-mail unit maintainance and documentation. Configuring PBX handsets. Delivering equipment. Mutations in the PBX.

1991 - 1998: Soundengineer

At Simplon youthcentre and for various bands, occasasions, concerts and studio-recordings. I'm one of the founders of the Simplon Audio Group and was the most active member and I've been the leader for years. I recorded many demos. I didn't avoid experimenting and added a lot ideas to the recordings. I taught many musicians the basics of sound technique which were practical for them, such as monitor technique and microfone technique. I also instructed beginning sound engineers.

Opleidingen:

2010-01	Snort certified professional.
2009-06	Intake training, Snow B.V.
2009-06	LDAP in a nutshell, Snow B.V.
2009-03	Sun Certified System Administrator for the Solaris 10
	OS part I (CX-310-200), Sun Microsystems
2009-03	Sun Certified System Administrator for the Solaris 10
	OS part II (CX-310-202), Sun Microsystems
2009-02	Sun Solaris 10 Training Special (NL-EC-170-SOL), Sun
	Microsystems
2009-01	Netapp ONTAP in a nutshell, Snow B.V.
2009	Various internal p-level trainings and Coaching
2008-12	ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management
	(based on V2), EXIN Certification
2008-11	Autumn conference 2008: Mobility, NLUUG
2008-05	Linux Professional Institute Certified Level 2, Linux
	Professional Institute
2008-05	Spring conference 2008: Security, NLUUG
2008-01	ESD certification
2007-09	EuroBSD Copenhagen 2007, BSDCon
2007-08	Linux Professional Institute Certified Level 1, Linux
	Professional Institute
1999-2007	Self study for Unix administrator
1998	Six week internal course Telecom maintainance at In-
	terCAI Academy
1989-1998	Self-study Sound engineer
1989–1993	MTS Electronics, Aa-college Groningen
1987–1989	HIO (hogere informatica opleiding), HBO Groningen
1982–1987	HAVO Almere College Dronten/Kampen
	Dutch; English; Math;
	Physics; Chemistry; Economics

Other information:

I speak English fluently. I speak French and German proficiently. Dutch is my native language.

My hobbies are paragliding, fitness, chess, walking, music, movies and wasting time on the internet.

The most recent version of this document 5 can be found on my homepage 6 , where you can find a lot more about things I'm doing.

 $^{^{5} \}verb|http://homepage.boetes.org/documents/cvHBoetes_english.pdf|$

⁶http://homepage.boetes.org/